Resume | Jason Yao

+1 (949) 335-2639 | JasonYao@nyu.edu | github.com/JasonYao | linkedin.com/in/jasonyaonyu

About Me

I am an undergraduate student in New York, NY, studying computer science with an interest in full-stack web development and general software development. I have a strong love for discovering new and efficient ways to solve problems, and have general coding experience with Python, C, Java, and PHP.

Education

New York University

New York, NY

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science (College of Arts & Sciences) Expected Graduation: May 2017

- Theoretical Technical Knowledge: <u>Data Structures</u>, <u>Basic Algorithms</u>, <u>Computer Systems</u>: <u>Organisation</u>, <u>Operating Systems</u>
- **Practical Technical Knowledge**: <u>Large Scale Web Applications</u>, <u>Parallel Computing</u>, Algorithmic Problem Solving

Employment Summary

Ivy Tech Capital - *Start-up Software Developer Internship* (Jun. 2016 – Aug. 2016) **Beijing, China** With ITC my role was to learn from start-up entrepreneurs and then mock-create a start-up at ITC's incubator. I learned start-up centric financial concepts studies and market research/analysis, and then built and pitched a minimum viable product (MVP) for the incubator investors at the end. In that pitch contest, our team won **2nd place** out of 10 start-up teams.

Phi Kappa Sigma Delta Phi Chapter - *Technology Chair* (Jan. 2015 - present) New York, NY My role as Delta Phi's technology chair involved designing, developing, and maintaining a <u>chapter</u> website for the organisation in a scalable, efficient, and secure fashion. As technology chair I also managed all core communication services (Facebook, twitter, Signal, etc.), headed the technology committee, and built an <u>automated room-booker</u> for chapter needs.

HiVi Acoustics – *Software Developer Internship* (May 2015 – August 2015) **Los Angeles, CA** I designed and developed with a small team a planned upgrade and translation of an e-commerce site, and developed server-side skills including Unix-system familiarity, server upkeep and administration, and modern continuous delivery (CD) approaches. I also learned foundational development practices such as local virtualisation and source control usage.

Recent Projects

QR-Code Item Finder: Demo site available here: http://54.165.38.12/

The purpose of this project was to create a full-fledged scalable web application that showcased security & scalability in the design and execution of the website service. We built a service that utilised concepts learned in class that included logical & physical sharding (simulated), cache write-through (due to low write, and high read rates), and manual load balancing (simulated). Code repository is here.

Skills, Activities & Interests

Languages: Native fluency in English, conversational proficiency in Mandarin

Programming Languages: C, Java, Python, MATLAB, LaTeX, Markdown, Bash, PHP

Activities: NYU Varsity Fencing (Men's Foil), Phi Kappa Sigma Fraternity Delta Phi Chapter,

Tech@NYU, ACM@NYU, Women in Computing (WinC@NYU)

Interests: Programming, entrepreneurship, charity, fencing, and running